So, what do you do when you find outliers and raw price data?
对于原始股价数据和离群值你该怎么处理呢？
Well, although at least large institutions,
至少在大型机构
co- traders usually have a team of people to clean data for them.
量化分析师通常都有一个团队来帮助他们清理数据
They may run into situations where they need results fast.
但是也有可能遇到需要快速获得结果的情形
The easiest and quickest way to determine if the extreme value is real,
判断极端值数据是否真实或填充缺失数据点的最便捷方式是
or fill in a missing data point is to cross check with another data source.
与其他数据源进行交叉验证
If it's a one off point,
如果只出现一次
you can remove or replace it with data from a secondary source manually.
可以手动删掉它或用第二个数据源中的数据替换掉
You might think of replacing these data with some mean of the surrounding data.
你可能想要用周围数据的均值替换这些数据
This is not done often because it risks incorporating
这种做法不太常见
information from the future into those days data.
因为可能会包含未来的信息
Inaccuracy due to the use of information that would not have been known or
使用在分析期间未知或无法获得的信息
available during the period being analyzed is called Lookahead Bias.
而导致的不准确性称为前视偏差
Think about it. If you were trying to fill in that missing datum by averaging
思考下如果你尝试通过对缺少数据所在的日期
data from the surrounding days on the day for which the datum is missing,
前后日期的数据取平均值来填充缺少的值
you wouldn't be able to because you wouldn't know what the price would be in the future.
则无法这么做 因为不知道未来的价格是多少
Lookahead bias is a bias because using
前视偏差之所以是偏差
unknowable data from the future will consistently make your results look better.
是因为使用未来的未知数据将不断使结果看起来更好
The main problem with using future data in signal research is that
在信号研究中使用未来数据的主要问题是
any kind of strategy based on that research would be impossible to execute.
基于这种研究的任何策略都无法执行
One common mistake is to use closing prices of
一种常见错误是使用当前日期或未来日期的收盘价
the current day or a future date to calculate the trading signal for the same day.
计算同一天的交易信号
But of course, a strategy that says to make a trade during
当然 在一天当中根据同一天的收盘价
the day based on a closing price for that same day would be impossible to implement.
进行交易的策略根本无法执行
It may not seem to make much of a difference in cases where you
如果是在历史分析中使用这类数据
were using the data for some kind of historical analysis,
区别可能不大
but to be safe, it makes sense to simply substitute
但是保险起见 建议在信号研究阶段
a missing closing price with the previous closing price during signal research.
使用之前的收盘价替换缺失的收盘价
However, keep in mind that it is recommended to keep the missing data
但是 在回溯测试过程中建议保留缺失的数据
during back testing because they may represent a real non-tradable event.
因为它们可能表示真实的不可交易事件
For example, stock A may not have traded for
例如 股票 A 可能某一天没有交易
a day and thus it's closing price would have been missing.
所以缺少收盘价
In your back test your data should reflect this and
在回溯测试中 数据应该体现这一点
your strategy should not attempt to place trades on stock a during that day.
投资策略不应尝试在这一天对股票 A 进行交易